(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
静寂に響いてよ My Howling
Echo through the silence, my howling
Howling
作詞・作曲：ZAQ 編曲：KanadeYUK
Lyrics/Composition: ZAQ Arrangement: KanadeYUK
瞬きは弧描き、月へ響く
A twinkle draws an arc, echoing to the moon
爪弾く道 金瞳の群れ 共に嘆く夜
The strummed path, the golden-eyed pack,
nights we lament together
伝播する想いは心強くする
These feelings that spread make the heart stronger
共に行こうよ 隣に君がいるから
Let's go together, because you're by my side
私は迷わない
I will not hesitate
光射す道へ
Toward the path where the light shines
LISTEN TO MY HOWLING...
狼が止まることはない
The wolf will never stop
聞こえますか
Can you hear me?
夜充通信
作詞・作曲・編曲：堀江晶太
Yakou Tsuushin
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Horie Shouta
ハローハロー 聞こえますか そっちは何年？
Hello, hello, can you hear me? What year is it there?
正しく分かり合う手段は一つじゃないさ
There's more than one way to truly understand each other
例えお星様はどこへ行くのか
さよならはいつ誰が決めるの
No matter where the stars go
Who decides when to say goodbye, and when?
その手に触れようと願ってる 本当さ
I'm wishing to touch those hands, it's the truth
永遠の夜光 君に歌う
An eternal night light, I sing for you
世界中が君にいじわるでも
Even if the whole world is mean to you
思い出して 覚えていて 瞼の裏
ずっとまた会えるからね
Recall it, remember it, behind your eyelids
We can always meet again
穏やかに 健やかに 流れる月
君だって私だって
Gently, healthily, the moon flows
Both you and me
消えるのは 言葉だけ
The only things that disappear are words
ふんわり君を抱きしめてあげるからね
泣かないで
I'll gently hold you close
So please don't cry
夜明けのメロウ
作詞：MegRi 作曲・編曲：如月結愛 (Arte Refact)
Yoake no Melow
Lyrics: MegRi Comp/Arr: Kisaragi Yua (Arte Refact)
変わりゆくもの 終わりゆくもの
Things that change, things that end
一つ 瞬くように
Like a single twinkle
確かめていたい 霞む世界に
I want to be sure, in this hazy world
私はどうか 忘れないで
Please don't ever forget me
君の記憶の どこへ
Somewhere in your memories
淡く甘く
Fading faintly and sweetly
滲んで ひとつになって
Becoming one as we blur
漂うだけ
Just drifting
泣き出しそうな
As if ready to cry
夜の隙間を縫って
Stitching through the gaps of the night
私は行く 夜明けのメロウ
I'll go, the mellow of dawn
君の隣で
By your side
溶けて消えるほど 生きて
Living until I melt and disappear
はい、というわけで！
All right, and with that!
大神ミオ生誕ライブ「晴れ時々にわかミオ」
Ookami Mio's Birthday Live, "Sunny With a Chance of Mio"
を見に来てくれてありがとー！
Thank you so much for coming to see it!
ちょっと自己紹介からいこうかな？
Maybe I'll start with a self-introduction?
ということで、
So...
うちうち、うちだよ！大神ミオだよ！
It's me, me! It's Ookami Mio!
はあー。よろしくお願いします。
Phew. Nice to meet you.
まあだいたいの人はね、知ってると思うんですけど
Well, I think most people know who I am,
まあこれを機会に見てみようかなっていう人は、ぜひぜひ大神ミオよろしくお願いいたします。
but if you're watching this for the first time, please get to know Ookami Mio.
えー、今日のハッシュタグはこちら！
Um, today's hashtag is this one!
たくさんポストの方、よろしくお願いいたします！
Please post a lot about it!
さてさて、生誕ライブ始まったわけなんですけど
Well then, the birthday live has begun,
ステージすごくない？
isn't the stage amazing?
こんなに大きいステージ作ってもらったよ！
I had such a huge stage built for me!
なんかビルとか建ってるし、
There are even buildings standing here,
ここは一体どこなんだということで、天井もめっちゃ広いんですけど
so where on earth are we? The ceiling is also super high.
なんかね、うちがね、魔法の言葉を言うとね、なんかどっかが開くらしいんだよね。
Apparently, when I say a magic word, somewhere will open up.
ちょっと開けてみろって言われてる。
I've been told to try opening it.
ちょっと行きますよ。
Here I go.
せーの、オープン！
Ready, and... Open!
うわーすごい！
Whoa, incredible!
神々しい、うわー空だー！
So divine, wow, it's the sky!
ということで、タイトルからちょっとだけ予想はついくかもなんですけど、
So, you might have guessed a bit from the title,
晴れだったり、雨だったり、昼だったり、夜だったり、
but whether it's sunny, rainy, day, or night,
いろんな様子を表現したいっていう、うちの要望を全部叶えてもらいました！
all my requests to express various conditions have been fulfilled!
わーすごい！素敵なステージありがとうございます。
Wow, amazing! Thank you so much for this wonderful stage.
大きいよー！
It's so big!
はい。えー、運営さんどうもありがとうございます。いつもお世話になってます。
Yes. Um, thank you very much to the staff. Thanks for everything as always.
ということで、みんなもね、いっぱいお祝いしてくれてどうもありがとうね。
And to everyone as well, thank you so much for all the celebrations.
うちはホロライブに入って、もう6回目の誕生日なんですけれども
It's already my sixth birthday since joining Hololive,
まーなんか、なー、なんか、なんかしらあって、いつもね誕生日ケーキ食べれてないんだけどね。
but, well, something always happens and I haven't been able to eat my birthday cake.
今年は、まーちょっと体調を崩したこともあり、ちょっと多分ケーキは食べられないんだけど、
This year, I haven't been feeling too well, so I probably won't be able to eat cake either,
今日はその代わりに、大好きなホロライブのメンバーと一緒に、たくさん歌っちゃおうと思ってます！
but instead, I'm planning to sing a lot today with my beloved Hololive members!
それぞれメンバーと一緒に歌いたい曲を、たくさん選曲してみました。
I've chosen many songs that I want to sing with each member.
ここからホロメンとのコラボ曲、盛りだくさんでお送りしちゃいます。
From here on, we'll be bringing you plenty of collaboration songs with Hololive members.
あー、もう次の曲の準備をしなきゃいけないかもしれ、しれない。
Ah, I might, might have to get ready for the next song already.
噛んじゃったけど。最後までみんなたくさん楽しんでってね。
I tripped over my words there. Everyone, please enjoy yourselves until the very end!
じゃあちょっと準備してくるね。
Well then, I'll go get ready.
楽しんでね！
Have fun!
晴る
Sunny
作詞・作曲：n-buna
Lyrics/Composition: n-buna
あなたは風のように
You are like the wind
目を閉じては夕暮れ
Closing my eyes, it's evening
何を思っているんだろうか
I wonder what you are thinking about
まぶたを開いていた
My eyelids were open
貴方の目はビイドロ
Your eyes are like glass beads
少しだけ晴るの匂いがした
There was a slight scent of clear weather
晴れ
Sunny
花よ咲け
Bloom, flowers
咲いて晴るのせい
Bloom, it's because of the clear sky
降り止めば雨でさえ
If it stops falling, even the rain
貴方を飾る晴る
Is the clarity that adorns you
胸を打つ音よ、鳴け
Beat of the heart, resound
僕ら晴る風
We are the clear wind
あの雲も
Even those clouds...
あの雲も越えてゆけ
Go beyond those clouds too
遠くまで 遠くまで
Far away, far away
貴方は晴れ模様に
You're like a sunny sky
目を閉じては青色
Closing my eyes, I see blue
何が悲しいのだろうか
I wonder what's so sad
まぶたを開いている
I'm opening my eyelids
貴方の目に映ったら
If I'm reflected in your eyes
今少し雨の匂いがした
I smelled a bit of rain just now
泣き出しそうな空よ泣け
O sky that looks ready to cry, go ahead and cry
泣いて雨のせい
Cry and blame it on the rain
降り頻る雨でさえ
Even the pouring rain
雲の上では晴れる
Will clear up above the clouds
土を打つ音よ鳴れ
Sound of rain hitting the earth, ring out
僕ら春荒れ
We are a spring storm
あの海も越えてゆけ
Go beyond that sea too
遠くまで 遠くまで
Far away, far away
通り雨 草をなびかせ
A passing shower makes the grass sway
ひつじ雲 あれも春のせい
Altocumulus clouds, those are also because of spring
風のよう 胸に春乗せ
Like the wind, carrying spring in our hearts
春を待つ
Waiting for spring
晴れに晴れ空よ裂け
Sunny to sunnier, O sky, split open
裂いて春のせい
Split open and blame it on spring
降り止まぬ雨でさえ
Even the unending rain
貴方を飾る春
Is the spring that adorns you
胸を打つ音奏で
Playing the sound that beats in our hearts
僕ら春風
We are a spring breeze
音に聞く晴るの風
The legendary spring breeze
さあこの歌よ凪げ！
Now, let this song calm the storm!
晴れに晴れ花よ咲け
Sunny to sunnier, O flowers, bloom
咲いて春のせい
Bloom and blame it on spring
あの雲も越えてゆけ
Go beyond those clouds too
遠くまで 遠くまで
Far away, far away
今なんじゃない？
Isn't it the time now?
メラメラとたぎれ
Seethe and burn like a blaze
眠っているだけの正義 こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
The justice that's just been asleep Even someone like me wants to be your hero
Lalala...
かっこいい君には 僕じゃ頼りないのかなんて
I wonder if I'm not reliable enough for a cool person like you
そりゃそうだよな だって今もこうして迷ってる
Of course that's the case, since even now I'm lost like this
Lalala... 手を取ってくれないか
Lalala... won't you take my hand?
Lalala... ギブアンドテイクさ
Lalala... it's give and take
Lalala... 君が僕のヒーローだったように
Lalala... just like how you were my hero
今なんじゃない？
Isn't it the time now?
メラメラとたぎる こんな僕にも潜む正義が
Seething and burning like a blaze The justice that's hidden even in me
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて ほら気付けば手を握っている
Driven by an uncontrollable urge Look, before I knew it, I was holding your hand
いったい全体そんなに荷物を背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Where on earth are you going, carrying such a heavy burden?
ねえねえ待って僕にちょっと預けてみては？
Hey, hey, wait, why not try entrusting it to me for a bit?
信じてばかりの僕と
Just me who only keeps believing,
信じることが怖い君と
And you who are afraid to believe,
どちらが正しいのかなんて
As for which of us is correct,
誰にも分からない
No one can tell.
Lalala...
僕らだけの世界に
In a world that belongs only to us,
Lalala...
ギブとテイクさ
It's give and take.
Lalala...
補い合えた暁には
When we finally complement each other,
同じ夢を見たい
I want to see the same dream.
君はかっこいいと苦しめて
I say you're cool, and it hurts you,
ひとりぼっちにさせたのは
And what made you feel all alone
少し僕のせいなんだよな ごめんね
Was partly my fault, I'm sorry.
だけど見るべきはリアルだ
But what you should see is reality,
今こそ僕が助けるんだ
Now is the time for me to save you.
抱えないで信じて頼ってほしいんだ
Don't hold it in; believe and rely on me.
今なんじゃない メラメラとたぎる
Isn't now the time? Blazing and boiling,
こんな僕にも潜む正義が
The justice that hides even within me.
どうしようもない衝動に駆られて
Driven by an uncontrollable urge,
ほら気付けば手を握っている
Look, before I knew it, I was holding your hand.
放っておけない そんなに荷物を
I can't leave you alone, carrying so much luggage,
背負い込んでどこへ行くの
Where are you going with all that on your back?
ほんのちょっと僕にちょっと預けてみては？
How about letting me carry some of it for a bit?
こんな僕も君のヒーローになりたいのさ
Even someone like me wants to be your hero.
キミノコエヲキカセテ
Let me hear your voice!
サアボウケンシテミナイ
Come on, won't you go on an adventure?
タノシイコトハジメヨウ
Let's start something fun!
遊びたい！
I want to play!
ぜったい！
Definitely!
たい！たい！たい！たい！
-ly! -ly! -ly! -ly!
JOYとJOYとPOPなベイベー
Joy and joy and pop baby!
JOYとJOYとHAPPYなピーポー
Joy and joy and happy people!
ヨワムシナンカジャナイ
I'm not a coward!
ジシンアリゲニピースサイン
A confident peace sign!
キミノヒトミニキスシテ
Kissing your eyes,
笑いたい！
I want to laugh!
ぜったい！
Definitely!
たい！たい！たい！たい！
-ly! -ly! -ly! -ly!
JOYとJOYとYOUきなベイベー
Joy and joy and courageous baby!
JOYとJOYとHAPPYなSayイエー
Joy and joy and happy, say yeah!
君の心はそうもっと Do Do
Your heart is, yeah, more do-do!
僕の心もそういっそ Good Good
My heart is also, yeah, rather good-good!
ハジケテンジャナイッツォジョイフル
Aren't we bursting? More like, joyful!
ぱぴぷぺぽぱぴぷぺぽ Yeah
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po pa-pi-pu-pe-po yeah!
JOYとJOYとPOPなベイベー
Joy and joy and pop baby!
JOYとJOYとHAPPYなピーポー
Joy and joy and happy people!
ドキドキしちゃうのナンデダロウ
Why does my heart race?
ズキズキしちゃうのナンデダロウ
Why does it throb?
この指にとまるのはどんな運命なんだ
What kind of fate is it that lands on this finger?
ぜんぶしたいな
I want to do it all!
じょいふるだって終わっちゃう
Even Joyful will come to an end,
エブリバディいつか終わっちゃう
Everybody ends eventually,
いつもこの時を
Always this moment...
最終型はもっと修正なして
The final form, without more correction,
どー We Do We Do
Do- We Do We Do
どー ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ ぱぴぷぺぽ
Do- pa-pi-pu-pe-po pa-pi-pu-pe-po...
いたい！たい！たい！たい！
Definitely! -ly! -ly! -ly!
JOYとJOYとYOUきなベイベー
Joy and joy and courageous baby!
ダッシュ！
Dash!
HAPPYなSay イェー！
Say a happy 'Yeah!'
君の心はそう もっと Do Do
Your heart is, yeah, doing more 'Do Do'
僕の心もそう いっそ Goo Goo
My heart is too, rather 'Goo Goo'
初めてのんじゃな～い It's Joyful
It's not the first time~ It's Joyful
ぱぴぷぺぽぱぷぅ～
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po-pa-pu~
JOY!
はい「冴えなし」愛情論で おねだり
Yes, begging with a "dull" theory of love
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン 汚りだ（Dirty） 汚りだ
Da-da-da-darling, dirty, dirty
会いたい衝動 埋めてよ ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン
Fill up my urge to see you, da-da-da-darling
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ…
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na...
無い無い清純 感情が行ったり来たり
No, no purity, emotions going back and forth
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ…
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na...
無い無い純情 感傷でダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン
No, no innocence, sentimentality da-da-da-darling
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン だ、あ、え、だ、って
Da-da-da-darling, saying "D-A-E-D-A"
ママにゴロンゴロンににゃにゃ 食いじ食いじダイエットで
Rolling around for Mama, meow meow, greedy diet
もう精一杯で罪 ボロ布世界で無理
Doing my best, a sin, impossible in a world of rags
病み明かしてんだって承認承認接待だ
Stayed up sick, it's recognition, recognition, hospitality
何もない 何もない 私何もない ねえ
Nothing, nothing, I have nothing, hey
はしたない はしたない 私はしたない ねえ
Improper, improper, I'm improper, hey
わからない わからない わかるわからない はい
I don't know, I don't know, I understand I don't know, yes
地団駄は全部隠して
Hide all the floor-stomping
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン ファニー
Da-da-da-darling, darling, darling, funny
はい「絶えなし」愛情論で 冷めたり
Yes, cooling down with a "never-ending" love theory
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン 無理だ（Dirty） 汚りだ
Da-da-da-darling, impossible (dirty), dirty
会いたい衝動 止めてよ ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン
Stop my urge to see you, da-da-da-darling
踊れ 叫べ 踊れ ル・ラッパッパ
Dance, shout, dance, Ru-ra-pa-pa
踊れ 唄え 踊れ ル・ラッパッパ
Dance, sing, dance, Ru-ra-pa-pa
もうドキドキの 心臓ドキドキの
Already heart-pounding, heart-pounding
素顔全部なくして
Lose all your true face
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン ファニー
Da-da-da-darling, darling, darling, funny
どうしようもない感情論に 笑ったり
Laughing at helpless emotional theories
ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン 汚偽だ（Dirty） 汚みだ（Dummy）
Da-da-da-darling, dirty deception, dirty dummy
会いたい衝動 埋めてよ ダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン
Fill up my urge to see you, da-da-da-darling
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ…
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na...
無い無い反応 返答を期待したり
No, no response, expecting an answer
ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ・ナ…
Na-na-na-na-na-na-na-na...
無い無い妄想 感傷でダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン
No, no delusion, sentimentality da-da-da-darling
無い無い感情 感傷でダ・ダ・ダ・ダーリン
No, no emotion, sentimentality da-da-da-darling
おねだり
Begging
ドキドキして ルー
My heart is pounding, roo
いきますよー！
Here we go!
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Innocent! Innocent! Pretty girl innocent!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Sparkling as expected, even more dizzy
ねえ、言ったよね？ 年齢なんて関係ないってさ
Hey, you said it, right? That age doesn't matter
そういう面倒くさいのも含めて愛してくれるって
That you'd love me including those troublesome parts
ねえねえ言ったよね？言わない？言ってない？
Hey, hey, you said it, right? You don't say? You didn't say it?
ふーん、そういうこと言うんだ。
Hmm, so that's what you're saying.
ちなみにこの船では美少女無罪が適用されますけど？
By the way, "pretty girl innocence" applies on this ship, you know?
まかせて！魔法で若返り
Leave it to me! Rejuvenation with magic
ヒミツの素顔はキミにだけ トクベツですよー
My secret true face is only for you, it's special
Ah アタシ厄介よ
Ah, I'm troublesome
Ah 皆なんかじゃ
Ah, with everyone else
はしゃげないわ 近頃はね
I can't frolic, lately you see
宝の島にしてほしい気分 出航ー！！
Feeling like wanting you to make me a treasure island, set sail!!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, pretty girl innocent
キミの一番 目指して ヨーソロー！
Aiming for your number one, steady as she goes!
本当は自信ないけど 頑張っちゃう（あーほーい！）
Actually I'm not confident, but I'll do my best (Ahoy!)
きゅんきゅんきゅんきゅん きゅるんるん
Kyun kyun kyun kyun, kyurun run
恋する気持ち17歳
Feelings of love, 17 years old
0時になっちゃうわ オトナの時間
It's almost midnight, adult time
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Sparkling as expected, even more dizzy
ドキドキして ルー
My heart is pounding, roo
まだ早い♡
Still too early
ミオマリンともっと歌えー！
Sing more with MioMarine!
はにょ～ 頑張るぞ
Hanyo~ I'll do my best
だっ だっ ダメですか？ フリルの服着たら
Is, is, is it no good? If I wear frilly clothes
そんなことないよ！
That's not true!
だっ だっ だって魔法少女になってみたい
B-b-because I want to try becoming a magical girl
ギリギリ有罪！？ GUILTY
Barely guilty!? GUILTY
進路はなんなん星 ちょっぴり足んない積極性
Course is Nannan Star, a little lack of aggressiveness
結局キミも もっと若い子？
In the end, do you also want younger girls?
なんだってするから 見捨てないでキミタチ
I'll do anything, so don't abandon me, everyone
ちょっとイイトコ見てみたーい！
I want to see something good!
Ah たまにいじけちゃう
Ah, sometimes I get sulky
Ah それでもいいの？
Ah, is that still okay?
年頃だもん 本気にしちゃう
I'm at that age, so I'll take it seriously
嵐の中も 一緒に行こう？
Even in a storm, let's go together?
出航ー！！
Set sail!!
ハートにジャブ 美少女無罪
A jab to the heart, pretty girl innocent
あれれ どーした？ めんどくさい なんて言っちゃって
Oh my, what's wrong? Saying things like "troublesome"
かまってくれる キミが好き
I like you for looking after me
きゅんきゅんきゅんきゅん きゅるんるん
Kyun kyun kyun kyun, kyurun run
優しくしてね17歳
Be gentle with me, 17 years old
突っ込んで経験値 お楽しみChu♡
Diving in for experience points, having fun kiss
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Sparkling as expected, even more dizzy
ドキドキして ルー
My heart is pounding, roo
ああ、お許しくだだ～い！このマリンの…
Ah, please forgive me~! This Marine's...
魅力！魔力！不可抗力！
Charm! Magic! Irresistible!
罪な女ね？
What a sinful woman, right?
離さないで つかまっていて
Don't let go, hold on tight.
世界の広さ 見せたるから！
I'll show you how big the world is!
出航ー！！
Set sail!!
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, beautiful girl is innocent.
キミの一番 目指して
Aiming to be your number one.
ヨーソロー！
Steady as she goes!
冗談も 大好きだけど
I love jokes too, but...
真剣よ
I'm serious.
Ahoy!!
きゅっ きゅるん きゅっ きゅるん
Kyu kyurun kyu kyurun.
恋する気持ち 517歳
Feelings of love, 517 years old.
0時になっちゃうわ オトナの時間
It's about to be midnight, adult time.
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Sparkling as expected, more dizzy.
ドキドキして ルージュ まだ早い♡
Heart pounding, rouge, it's still too early♡
無罪！無罪！美少女無罪！
Innocent! Innocent! Beautiful girl is innocent!
マリン！マリン！マリンは無罪！
Marine! Marine! Marine is innocent!
やっぱキラキラ もっとクラクラ
Sparkling as expected, more dizzy.
マリンじゃなくて マリン船長だもん！
It's not Marine, it's Captain Marine!
電波電波飛ばして 絶賛感電中
Sending out radio waves, currently being electrocuted.
あなたにもわすれたいことかないこと
Things you don't want to forget...
あるのかしらね
...I wonder if they exist.
知らない映画なのに 涙をながすのは
Crying even though it's a movie I don't know...
ドラマチックが足りていないからよ
...it's because there's not enough drama.
そんな事にも付かないこと
Things I don't even notice...
くだらないこと考えてばかりね
...just thinking about trivial things.
雨が上がれば愛もその横顔も
When the rain stops, love and that profile...
誰かのものになるのでしょう
...will probably belong to someone else.
嘘っぱちのファンデーションも全部 今夜のためよ
All the fake foundation is for tonight.
なのになに一体全体 どうしてどうして何故何故怒ってんの？
But why, in the world, are you angry?
不安定なカンデラ どこまで行くの
Unstable candela, how far will it go?
あなた一切合切 放り去ってもう
You throw everything away now.
冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
It's no joke, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって 如何にもならないぜ
Even when that time comes, it can't be helped.
曖昧な本当なんて メランコリ化するだけ
Ambiguous truth just turns into melancholy.
あたしをさらって 今 テイクオンミー
Take me away now, take on me.
はあ ちゃんちゃらおかしな法度ばっかで 食指がピクリともしないわ
Ah, just ridiculous laws, I don't have the slightest appetite.
実体のない感情放っておいたって 策略なんてありゃせんのに何故
Even if I leave my formless emotions alone, there's no scheme, so why?
うん ああもう懲り懲りよ あたしの癪に障る気質も
Yeah, ah, I've had enough of my annoying temperament.
じっと堪えて取り繕っては とうとう臨界点
Enduring and keeping up appearances, finally reaching the critical point.
年から年中リップサービス 鈍感かましては辟易
Lip service all year round, fed up with being insensitive.
どんがらガッシャンフィールガールは 涙の目にも鬼
Dongara gashan feel girl is a demon even in teary eyes.
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいで あなたの話は一向に聞き取れない
Now, because of the music in my head, I can't hear you at all.
少しは全うなこと言って
Say something a bit more sensible.
回り出すターンテーブル ねえ全部忘れさせてよ
Spinning turntable, hey, make me forget everything.
だけど一体全体 どうしてどうして何故何故怒ってんの？
But in the world, why why are you angry?
不安定なカンデラ 消えないまんまね
Unstable candela, still doesn't go out.
あなた一口二口 食い違ってももう
You and I are at odds by a bit or two now.
冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
It's no joke, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって 如何にもならないぜ
Even when that time comes, it can't be helped.
曖昧な本当なんて メランコリ化するだけ
Ambiguous truth just turns into melancholy.
あたしを今
Me, now.
冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
It's no joke, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって 如何にもならないぜ
Even when that time comes, it can't be helped.
不安定ないわ 感情なんてランドリーで落とすだけ
No unstable, just dropping emotions in the laundry.
あたしと確かめ合ってイエロー・マジック
Verify with me, yellow magic.
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous.
その時が来たって 如何にもならないぜ
Even when that time comes, it can't be helped.
曖昧な本当なんて メランコリ化するだけ
Ambiguous truth just turns into melancholy.
あたしを逆さまって今 テイクオンミー
Turn me upside down now, take on me.
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、連続で7曲もお送りしましたー！
And so, we've brought you seven songs in a row!
わーい！
Yay!
いっぱい歌った歌った。
I sang and sang a lot.
みんなめっちゃ可愛かったなー。
Everyone was so cute.
半分うちの趣味...ま、というか半分というか、ま、ほほど、うちの趣味で選曲させてもらったんですけど。
Half of it was my own taste... well, instead of half, I chose the songs based on my taste.
ま、きっとね、みんなも、うちが歌うのが初めての楽曲ばかりだったと思うんですが、
Well, I'm sure for all of you, these were songs that you were hearing me sing for the first time,
みんなどうだったかなー？
how was it for everyone?
まだまだね、もうちょっと歌は続くんだいけれど、
The songs will continue for a bit longer, but...
その前に、皆さんお待ちかね！
before that, what you've all been waiting for!
グッズ...
Goods...
以上、グッズ紹介です！
That's all for the goods introduction!
イェーイ！
Yay!
今年のグッズは、何かな、何かな～、
I wonder what this year's goods are...
というわけで、はい、こちらです！
Well, here they are!
ババーン！
Baban!
今回も泉彩パパにキービジュアルを
書いてもらいました！
Once again, Izumi Sai-papa drew the key visual!
カッコ可愛いミオだ！ガオーポーズ！
It's a cool and cute Mio! Gao pose!
色々とね、ちょっともう見えちゃってるんですけれども、
You can already see a lot of things, but
まずは、こちら！
first, this!
アクリルスタンドです！
It's the acrylic stand!
このね、ガオーポーズのアクリルスタンド、
可愛いんだよね。
This gao-pose acrylic stand is so cute, isn't it?
しかもこれ、ただのアクリルスタンドではなくて、
And this isn't just any acrylic stand,
なんと！
it's...!
ミラーコーティングでキラキラしてます！
It has a mirror coating and is all sparkly!
うちがね、個人的にね、
キラキラのアクリルスタンド作りたくて、
I personally wanted to make
a sparkly acrylic stand,
わがままを聞いてもらって、
ミラーコーティングにしてもらいました。
so they listened to my request
and made it mirror-coated.
イェーイ！
Yay!
ミオファもね、足元にいてね、可愛いね。
Miofa is also there at the feet, it's cute.
うちも部屋に飾ろうっと。
I'm going to display it in my room too.
はい、そしてお次、二つ目は...
Okay, and next, the second item is...
Tシャツです！可愛い！
a T-shirt! Cute!
こちらもキービジュアルを使った
Tシャツとなっております。
This is also a T-shirt using the key visual.
泉彩パパに書いてもらったイラストなんだけど、
It's an illustration drawn by Izumi Sai-papa,
このね、カッコいいTシャツを作るために
書いてもらったと言っても過言ではない、
and it wouldn't be an exaggeration to say it was
drawn specifically to make this cool T-shirt,
イラストとなっておりまして、
ちょっとこうロックな感じに仕上げてもらいました。
it has a bit of a rock-style finish.
カッコいいからみんなも日常使いにいかがでしょうか。
Since it's cool, how about
using it for daily wear, everyone?
サイズは、ちょっと大きめのXLサイズ。
The size is a slightly larger XL.
プリントもね、すごい大きくて、結構目立つから、
The print is also really big and quite noticeable,
イベントに着て行って、ミオファをアピールしてね！
so wear it to events and show off that you're a Miofa!
そして、三つ目。サコッシュ！
And, the third item. A sacoche!
最近さ、なんか痛バを作ってる人、いっぱい見かけるし、
Lately, I've been seeing a lot of people
making "itabags," and
なんかホロライブ公式からも
たくさん痛バ用のバッグとか出してるの見て、
seeing Hololive official releasing
a lot of bags for itabags...
ま、他のメンバーもね、バッグ出してるの見てさ、
うちもなんかバッグ、ミオファ用に作りたいかも、と思い、
Well, seeing other members release bags too
made me think I want to make a bag for Miofa,
サコッシュを作ってみました。
so I made a sacoche.
サコッシュなんで、お財布とか、スマホとかをね、
ちょっと入れとくのに良いんですけれども、
Since it's a sacoche, it's good for
putting your wallet or smartphone in.
外側のポケットが透明になってるから、
The outer pocket is transparent,
そこに缶バッジを入れたりとか、
ちょっと痛バにすることもできるし、
so you can put tin badges in there
or make it a mini-itabag.
なんかこうちょっとグッズを入れて
アピールすることもできるバッグとなっております。
It's a bag where you can put some
goods in to show your support.
はい。まあ本当にね、
荷物用で一袋持って、
Yes. It's really like, carrying one bag for your luggage,
お財布とか取り出しやすいように、
このサコッシュを一個持ってると使いやすいかなと思って作りました。
and having this sacoche to easily take out
your wallet makes it very handy, I think.
そして最後の四つ目！
And the last and fourth item!
こちらです！
Here it is!
ぬいぐるみキーホルダー！可愛い！
A plushie keychain! So cute!
四つ目はぬいぐるみキーホルダー、
パーカー衣装のぬいぐるみバージョンです！
The fourth item is a plushie keychain,
the plushie version of the parka outfit!
これがね、パーカーは初めてなんだよ。めっちゃ可愛い！
This is the first time for the parka outfit. It's so cute!
サコッシュにね、一緒に付けてね、
ちょうどいいまであるよね。うん。
It would even look perfect attached to the sacoche. Yeah.
絶対一緒に付けてほしい！
一緒にうちをお出かけに連れて行ってほしいな。
I definitely want you to attach it!
I want you to take me with you on your outings.
パーカーの衣装だとね、こうちょっとラフな感じでね、
お出かけも連れて行きやすいんじゃないでしょうか。
With the parka outfit, it's a bit casual,
making it easy to take on outings, right?
あ、落とさないようにね、
皆さん絶対に気をつけてくださいね！
Ah, just make sure not to drop it,
everyone please be careful!
はい。そしてこの四つのグッズ、フルセットで注文していただくと、
なんと！特典として、こちら！
And if you order the full set of these four items,
you get this as a bonus!
複製サイン入り＆メッセージ入りの
キービジュアルのダイカットステッカーと、
A die-cut sticker of the key visual
with a duplicated signature and message, and
あと、誕生日ありがとうのうちのお礼ボイスがついてきます！
わあ～！
a thank-you voice message from me
for the birthday! Wow!
いやあ、ちょっとね、フルセット購入悩んでいる方、
ぜひぜひこの特典もね、目当てに、
So, for those who are on the fence about the full set,
please aim for this bonus too,
あの、買ってくれたら嬉しいなって思うんですけれども、
I'd be happy if you bought it.
ま、お小遣いもね、限られてたりとかするから、
ま、お財布と相談しながら買ってください。よろしくお願いします。
Well, budgets can be limited, so please consider
your wallet before buying. Thank you.
ということで、以上グッズ紹介でした！
And that's all for the goods introduction!
今年の生誕グッズも盛りだくさんだね。
もう全部のね、グッズがね、うちが、
This year's birthday goods are also packed.
For all of the goods...
「こういうグッズが良いです」って言って全部監修して、
こだわりを持って作ったので、
I said "I want this kind of item" and supervised everything,
making them with great care.
ぜひぜひ皆さんのお手元に届くのを楽しみにしてます。
So I'm really looking forward to them reaching all of you.
ぜひ届いたら、えー、写真を撮ってポストしてくださいね。
When they arrive, please take a photo and post it!
うちのおうちに届くのもすっごい楽しみだなあ。
I'm also really looking forward to them arriving at my place.
というわけで、まだまだ、もうちょっとだけライブは続くのですが、
Anyway, the live will continue for a little bit longer,
まずはゲストでまだ出てないメンバーがいますよね。
う～、楽しみだ。
but first, there are still guest members who
haven't appeared yet, right? Ooh, I'm excited.
あの透明感のある声が良いんだよな。
That clear voice of theirs is so nice.
そしてなんと、なんと！新曲もお披露目しちゃいまーす！
やったー！
And also, and also! I'll be revealing
a new song! Yay!
ついにお披露目だ。
Finally, the reveal.
新曲はライブ終了後にMVをプレミア公開します！
The MV for the new song will have
its premiere after the live!
...公開する予定なので、そちらもよろしくお願いいたします。
...plan to release it soon, so please look forward to that as well.
そして、ライブの後はメンバーシップ限定アンコールライブもあるよ！
And after the live, there's a membership-only encore live!
すごい！メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブ、実は初めてやるんです。
Amazing! It's actually my first time doing a membership-only encore live.
よろしくお願いします、ぜひ見に来てね！
Please look forward to it, and come and watch!
それでは、大神ミオ生誕ライブ「晴れ時々にわかミオ」
Now then, Ookami Mio Birthday Live: "Partly Sunny, Sudden Mio"
残りも少なくなってきましたが
There isn't much left, but
最後まで一緒に盛り上がっていこう！
let's have a blast together until the very end!
点描の唄 / 作詞・作曲：大森元貴
Tenbyo no Uta / Lyrics & Composition: Motoki Ohmori
貴方の声で解れてゆく
Unraveling with your voice
忘れたくないと心が云う
My heart says I don't want to forget
思い出ばっか増えてゆく
Memories just keep on growing
ずっと側にいたい
I want to be by your side forever
泣き虫でもいいかな
Is it okay if I'm a crybaby?
強がらないでいいよ
You don't have to act tough
限りある恋だとしても
Even if it's a romance with a limit
出逢えて幸せです
I'm happy to have met you
いつまでも
Forever
続いて欲しいと願っている
I'm wishing for it to continue
手を取ることは出来ずとも
Even if we can't hold hands
私は貴方を好いている
I'm in love with you
貴方の夢で心安らぐ
Resting my heart in your dreams
目覚めたくないと僕は云う
I say I don't want to wake up
思い出ばっか増えてゆく
Memories just keep on growing
明日も側にいたい
I want to be by your side tomorrow too
どこまでも
Anywhere
鈍感な僕を叱って欲しい
I want you to scold my insensitive self
当たり前が壊れることに
To the breaking of what's normal
気づけないくらい子供だけど
I'm a child enough not to notice, but
ちゃんと僕は貴方を好いている
I truly am in love with you
私の
Mine
僕の
時間が止まればいいのに
If only time would stop
ほらまた期待をしてしまう
Look, I'm getting my hopes up again
ぐっと堪えてみるからさ
Because I'll try to hold it in
もし溢れ出したら瞳をちゃんと見てよ
If it overflows, look me straight in the eyes
貴方の影だけ伸びてゆく
Only your shadow keeps on growing
消えてしまわないでずっと
Please don't disappear, stay forever
この思いは変わらない
This feeling will not change
いつまでも
Forever
続いて欲しいと願っている
I'm wishing for it to continue
手を取ることは出来ずとも
Even if we can't hold hands
過ぎていく現在に抱きしめられている
Embraced by the passing present
私の
Mine
My
僕の
時間が止まればいいのに
I wish time would stop
今日を
Today
噛み締めていよう
I'll savor it
終わるな 夏よ終わるな
Don't end, summer, don't end
どうせなら...
If it's all the same...
...独りでゆこう
...I'll go alone
小心旅行
Broken-Heart Trip
今日は携帯は切っておこう
Today, I'll turn off my phone
ああ 乗り換えがわかんないや
Ah, I don't know the transfer
チャージしとこうか
Let's charge it up
いわゆる便利な世の中は
In this so-called convenient world
実はそれほど自由じゃない
It's actually not that free
ああ どうせ忘れちゃうのなら
Ah, if I'm going to forget anyway
上書きしちゃうのなら
If it's going to be overwritten
カメラは必要ないんだけど
I don't need a camera, but...
爪先は覚えていたい
I want my toes to remember
みたい ああ財布と携帯と充電器
It seems. Ah, wallet, phone, and charger
イヤホンは置いていく
I'll leave the earphones behind
身軽さでスキップの距離を稼ぐ
Cover distance with the lightness of a skip
ああ 感情はきっとこう
Ah, feelings are probably like this
ずっと背負うの合わない
Doesn't suit carrying them forever
今日は付けようかな
Maybe I'll put them on today
靴擦れじゃ困らない
I won't mind if I get blisters
私しか困らない
No one but me will mind
どうせ忘れちゃうとして
Even if I'm going to forget anyway
上書きしちゃうとして
Even if it's going to be overwritten
でもねいつかは思い出すから
But you see, I'll remember it someday
所詮独りですから
After all, I'm just alone
お土産はいつもマグネット
Souvenirs are always magnets
私と猫の分
For me and for the cat
それで十分
That's enough
ああ 見慣れた家電に安心する
Ah, I feel relieved by the familiar appliances
風はうちの匂い
The breeze smells like home
離れてぽつり浮かぶ
Floating alone after drifting away
私の輪郭
My silhouette
正真正銘の傷心旅行
A bona-fide broken-heart trip
誰にも言わずに家を出る
Leaving home without telling anyone
結局知っている店に逃げ
Eventually escaping to a familiar shop
この小心さえ愛してる
Even this timidity, I love it
ああ 放心状態の傷心旅行
Ah, a dazed broken-heart trip
戻ったよと伝えたい
I want to say I'm back
それが誰かわからないけど
I don't know who that would be, but...
あなただと言い
Saying it's you
ただいま帰ったよ
I'm home, I'm back
雨燦々
Ameyosandodo
選べよ 変わりゆく時代を
Choose it, the changing era
割り切れなくとも
Even if it doesn't quite add up
この瞬間 この舞台を 生き抜くから
I'll survive this moment, this stage,
手答えの無い
Even today,
今日でさえも
without a response,
紡ぐよ
I'll weave
でこぼこな此の道に
on this bumpy road,
降り注ぐ
The rain pours down
雨燦々と
brilliantly
悩ましく
and distressingly,
生き惑う
washing away even the sorrows
僕らの 悲しみさえも
of us who are lost in life
水に流してゆく
down the river.
錆びついた 自転車を 走らせて
Riding a rusty bicycle,
君へと向かうのさ
I'm heading towards you.
雨に濡れながら帰ろう
Let's go home while getting wet in the rain.
臨時ニュースの 報せでは
The news flash says
どうやらこれから
that from now on,
土砂降りの雨が降るらしい
it seems like it's going to rain heavily.
傘を忘れた ため息は
The sigh from forgetting my umbrella
夕立が連れてきた 夏の匂いに解けてゆく
unravels into the scent of summer brought by the evening shower.
過去を思う
The sorrows
悲しみたちが
of thinking about the past
雲となり 雨を打ちつける
become clouds and the rain beats down.
叫べよ 陽の晴れるまで
Shout until the sun shines,
声は 雨に掻き消され
your voice is drowned out by the rain.
今じゃ何処の 誰にも 届かなくても
Even if it doesn't reach anyone anywhere now,
手遅れに なってしまった 未来へさえも
even to a future that's already too late,
繋ぐよ そのバトンを
I'll connect that baton.
静かに 待ってる人がいる
There's someone waiting quietly.
雨燦々と 悩ましく
Rain pours down brilliantly and distressingly,
生き惑う
washing away even the sorrows
僕らの 悲しみさえも 水に流してゆく
of us who are lost in life down the river.
線路沿い 風を切り
Cutting through the wind along the tracks,
一直線に君へと向かうのさ
I'm heading straight for you.
雨に濡れながら帰ろう
Let's go home while getting wet in the rain.
ミオしゃ！お誕生日おめでとう！
Mio-sha! Happy birthday!
ミオ先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Mio-senpai, happy birthday!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ミオしゃ、お誕生日本当におめでとう！
Mio-sha, happy birthday, truly!
ミオ先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Mio-senpai, happy birthday!
ハッピーバースデーミオしゃ！
Happy birthday Mio-sha!
ミオちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Mio-chan, happy birthday!
ミオちゃん、ハッピーバースデー！
ミオちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Mio-chan, happy birthday!
ミオちゃん、誕生日おめでとう！
ミオしゃ、誕生日おめでとう！
Mio-sha, happy birthday!
厳しく 照りつける太陽よ
Oh sun that shines harshly,
僕らを導いておくれよ
please guide us.
未来を 歌う言葉だけが
Only the words that sing the future
嵐となり 森を吹き抜ける
become a storm and blow through the forest.
選べよ 変わりゆく時代を
Choose the changing times,
割り切れなくとも
even if they're not clear-cut.
この瞬間
This moment,
この舞台を 生き抜くから
I'll survive this stage,
青き春の 瞬きから 何度醒めようとも
no matter how many times I wake from the twinkle of blue spring.
紡ぐよ でこぼこな此の道に
I'll weave on this bumpy road,
降り注ぐ 雨燦々と 悩ましく
The rain pours down brilliantly and distressingly,
生き惑う
washing away even the sorrows
僕らの 悲しみさえも 水に流してゆく
of us who are lost in life down the river.
錆びついた
Riding
自転車を 走らせて君へと向かうのさ
a rusty bicycle, I'm heading towards you.
雨に濡れながら帰ろう
Let's go home while getting wet in the rain.
みんな、誕生日お祝いしてくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for celebrating my birthday!
幸せな誕生日になったよ！
It's been a happy birthday!
来年の誕生日も、こうやってお祝いできますように！
I hope we can celebrate next year's birthday like this too!
ありがとう！！
Thank you!!
晴れ時々にわかミオ
Sunny with Occasional Mio
#大神ミオ生誕ライブ2024
#OokamiMioBirthdayLive2024